

## Profile

I am a Python Backend developer with more than 7 years of experience in Python, SQL, and 3 years of experience in Cloud services.

Recently, I have been working as a developer in the European Union project to develop back-end and visualization (GUI) for the large-scale database at KTH Royal Institute of Technology.

I specialized in system design and development of overall service pipelines using many tools and techniques in Python, Bash, and SQL. The pipelines also included cloud services.

Also, I am a Doctoral student in Deep Learning. I have +3 years of experience with TensorFlow. Recently, I have been working on 6D pose estimation(Object detection, transfer learning). (DataBricks(or Horovod) and TensorFlowOnSpark)

-

Currently, I am looking for a great opportunity to combine all of my experiences as a developer & researcher on overall system design & development.

#### Education

Visiting Researcher | Computer Science, Halmstad University

January 2022 — June 2022

**Learning Systems** 

Big Data Parallel Programming

**Deep Learning** 

**Doctoral Student | Computer Science, Istanbul University** 

September 2019 — December 2022

Big Data Parallel Programming

Natural Language Processing

M.Sc. | Electric and Electronics Engineering, Istanbul University

September 2016 — December 2018

I was a member of Computational Intelligence and Machine Learning Research (CIML) Lab .

Topic: Estimation of energy consumption demand with artificial intelligence methods

Bachelor | Electric and Electronics Engineering, Fatih University

September 2010 — June 2015

Topic: Autonomous Traffic Assistant Implementation using FPGA

#### **Details**

Tenstagången 55, Lgh:2304 Stockholm, 16364 Sweden +46 76-445-8880 balsever@kth.se

#### Links

Interactive CV ResearchGate LinkedIn GitHub

#### **Skills**

**Machine Learning** 

**Deep Learning** 

Apache Spark

**Data Analysis** 

Python

SQL

CI/CD

AWS - GCP - Azure Cloud Services

# Employment History

#### Python Backend & GUI Developer at KTH, Stockholm

June 2022 — Present

I support the research team in the Nanochemistry Lab with the various software modules. I help them to store experiments' data in a manageable way, analyze using ML, and report using visualization tools. In this way, they have a chance to focus on their research topics and find their way through the experiments' data.

#### Data Engineer at RNV Analytics, Istanbul

October 2021 — June 2022

I designed and developed the stock allocation service(K-libre) by designing an algorithm on the Apache Spark engine. This made it possible to predict weekly +100k sales for +10k products with various sorties for more than 100 stores in less than 1 hour per client.

#### AI/ML Developer at Entertech Istanbul, Istanbul

January 2021 — June 2021

I worked both on backend development and NLP model design on a web platform for text generation.

#### AI/ML Developer at ITU Cekirdek, Istanbul

January 2020 — December 2020

I designed the hardware and software of Firearm detection device using Raspberry Pi as a portable security device.

### Software Developer at Corvisio, Istanbul

June 2019 — November 2019

I worked as a full-stack developer on CRM & OKR software.

#### Backend & System Design Engineer at Branson GPU Farm, Istanbul

January 2018 — April 2019

I worked as a backend system developer and as well as a network engineer on a mining cluster in bash scripting and python.

# PLC Programmer | Automation Engineer at Golday Kauçuk, Osmaniye

August 2016 — December 2016

- Performed minor maintenance and repairs on PLC machines and equipment as necessary.
- Oversaw production to ensure safe practices and equipment function.